Muzhe Wu

J 734-358-7357 | Menrw@umich.edu | ★ wumuzhe.com

github.com/henrw | Menry | Inlinkedin.com/in/muzhe-wu-573920223/

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest is in the intersection of artificial intelligence and human-computer interaction. I am specifically interested in creating interpretable and generalizable intelligent systems/agents that can learn from humans' behaviors and respond in alignment with humans' intents.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2021 - Apr 2023 (Expected)

• Advisors: Anhong Guo, Xu Wang, Veronica Perez-Rosas

• GPA: 3.95/4.00

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sept 2019 - Aug 2023 (Expected)

• GPA: 3.76/4.00 (ranked 21th out of 252 students in the class)

PUBLICATIONS, PRESENTATIONS & POSTERS

2022 <u>Muzhe Wu</u>*, Haocheng Ren*, Gregory Croisdale, Xu Wang, Anhong Guo. "Rubikon: A Multimodal Tutor for 3D Physical Task Learning." *Michigan Al Symposium 2022.* Poster Presentation & Demo. [Best Demo Award]

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Towards Understanding the Relation between Misinformation and Engagement | NLP

Jul 2022 - Present

LIT Lab (UMich) - Advisor: Veronica Perez-Rosas

- Designed a highly interpretable pipeline for online video engagement rating consisting of multimodal (visual, audio and textual) data preprocessing, mid-level feature extraction, time alignment, and an unbalanced early fusion model;
- Formally defined and labeled the engagement rate for the YouTube Prostate Cancer Dataset of 250 videos; trained the pipeline and performed a comparative study on the relation between misinformation and engagement.

MineDojo | RL Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Jim-Team (NVIDIA) - Advisor: Jim Fan

- Enabled GPU acceleration for scalable MineDojo RL simulation on headless machines by investigating EGL docker image;
- Created a meta-dataset of 20 open-ended, task-oriented datasets; scraped web data (e.g., GitHub repos for front-end development frameworks, DALL-E-2 showcase) to construct knowledge bases for generalist agent training.

Multimodal Cognitive Tutor | HCI

May 2022 - Present

HAIL Lab, Lifelong Learning Lab (UMich) - Advised by Xu Wang, Anhong Guo

- Designed a new ITS framework that leverages AI and AR and augments current tutorial methods for 3D physical tasks;
- Build the system for the Rubik's Cube learning, featuring domain/user modeling (by parsing and analyzing multimodal input, e.g., finger detection and ArUco markers), adaptive feedback (based on the abstractive knowledge tree and user/system initiatives), new task generation and low cognitive load guidance (voice aid, hidden side revelation, and spatial arrow).

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

- 2021, 2022 **Dean's Honor List** at the University of Michigan
 - 2021 Mathematical Contest in Modeling Meritorious Winner Prize (<9.5%)
 - 2020 University Physics Competition Silver Award (<3%)
- 2019, 2020 Undergraduate Excellent Scholarship at Shanghai Jiao Tong University (<10%)

SELECTED PROJECTS

Auxiliary Variables Improve Group Accuracy without Group Information [Link]

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

- Validated the effectiveness of auxiliary variables in the first stage of the JTT algorithm resolving the spurious correlation in ML;
- Designed, recreated, and collected visual datasets for spurious correlation research (e.g., configurable MNIST-CIFAR10).

FAD: Feature Alignment Discriminator for Text Summarization [Link]

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

- Introduced a BERT-based discriminator to BART text generator and designed feature alignment mechanism; achieved SOTA
 performance on CNN/DailyMail dataset for automatic abstractive text summarization.
- Trained the model with different settings (rDrop, layers used as features, and hyper-parameters) and compared it with baseline models (e.g., fine-tuned BART-base model) on ROUGE score.

Retro Game API for Reinforcement Learning [Link]

Feb 2022

- Developed an API for retro game simulation with reinforcement learning focus.
- Applied qym-retro integration tools to build runnable ROMs; designed a simulation environment with regulation methods and compatible utility classes (recorder, interactor, and dataset); designed a simulation GUI with observation and state information visualized; implemented wrapper classes for vision transform (random cropping, random convolution, and gaussian noise).

Mask Distribution Simulator [Link]

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

- Created a C++ program that evaluates the number of masks needed by cities in Hubei Province during the COVID-19 period and simulated the transportation of masks within the province along with subsequent impacts on pandemic situations.
- Applied the SIR model to classify people into different groups; set up parameters per factors including mask numbers and social distance; designed an interactive GUI that displays simulation results with OpenGL.

COMPETITIONS

Mathematical Contest in Modeling | Meritorious Winner Prize

Feb 2021

- · Modeled an ecosystem of different types of fungi (competitive relationships) with limited nutrients and simulated their long-term growth trends in various weather conditions.
- Applied Competitive Lotka Volterra Equations to formulate differential equations of fungi's growth; formulated correlation factors with geometry and necessary simplifications; evaluated weather factors with linear regression method; visualized simulation results in diagrams with MATLAB and Python.

University Physics Competition | Silver Medal

Nov 2020

- Formulated the route for a lightweight spacecraft traveling from earth to Saturn at the minimum fuel cost.
- Applied physics models, e.g., Conservation of Momentum, Kepler's Law, and Hohmann Transfer Orbit, to calculate the optimal track; established the relationships between fuel consumption and weight, distance, and time with Euler's Method.

SKILLS & RELATED COURSES

SKILLS

Python, C/C++, Java, Javascript, SQL, C#, MATLAB, R, Verilog Languages

Frameworks PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, SwiftUI, React, Vue, Gatsby, Flask, Bootstrap, Scrapy

ŁTFX, Unity, Mathematica, HTML, Figma, Linux (Ubuntu), Solidworks, Adobe Creative Suite **Tools**

RELATED COURSES

ML/NLP/CV Machine Learning; Natural Language Processing; Computer Vision; Science of Deep Learning;

User Interface Development; Human-Centered ML; Mind & Machine;

Other CS Web Systems; Operating Systems; Computer Organization; Data Structures & Algorithms;

Computer Security; Computer Science Foundations & Pragmatics;

Multivariable & Vector Calculus; Linear Algebra; Differential Equations; Discrete Math; Probability & Statistics; Math

EE Electrical Circuits; Signals & Systems; Logic Design; Analog Circuits;

VOLUNTEER & EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

Ann Arbor Figure Skating Club

June 2022 - Present

Competed and volunteered in adult figure skating competitions in Ann Arbor.

SJTU Basketball Association

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

Organized and refereed in collegial basketball matches at Shanghai Jiao Tong University.

High School Advisory

May 2020

Advised on the College Entrance Examination preparation for (≈700) senior students in Wenzhou No. 2 Foreign Language School.

UMJI Voluntary Association

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Regularly visited Jiangchuan Sunshine nursing house, hosting events and caring for people with mental difficulties.

REFERENCES

Anhong Guo Assistant Professor

Department of CSE University of Michigan ⊠ anhong@umich.edu

(personal website)

Xu Wang

Assistant Professor Department of CSE University of Michigan ⊠ xwanghci@umich.edu

(personal website)

Linxi "Jim" Fan

Research Scientist Al Research **NVIDIA** ⊠ linxif@nvidia.com

(personal website)

Verónica Pérez-Rosas

Research Scientist Department of CSE University of Michigan ⊠ vrncapr@umich.edu (personal website)